C. F. Voegelin Papers 1934-1970 Mss.Ms.Coll.68
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Works by Others, 1836-1968
  - "V. Sameness, Similarity, Analogy, Rules and Features", Aug. 1967; Householder, F. W.
  - "Language Factors Bearing on Culture Change Among Mennonites in Mexico"--Lecture, Dec. 1967; Jaquith, James R.
  - "Maximum Domains as Frames of Reference for the Ethnographic Eliciting of Major Lexemes in Contemporary Social Anthropology", Apr. 1964; Kiefer, T. M.
  - "Linguistic Acculturation in Nitinat", 1968; Klokeid, Terry J.
  - "The Verb Syntagmemes of Choapan Zapotec", Jul. 1964; Lyman, Larry
  - "Maps for South America" (Arranged by Florence Robinett from "Outline of South American Culture"), [ca. 1951]; Murdock, George P.
    -See also Ser. III-B, "Peopling of the New World (South America After North America)"
  - "The Hungarian Language", May 1966; Orosz, Robert A.
  - "Ecuador Quichua Phonology", n.d.; Orr, Carolyn
    -See also Ser. V-A, Quichua
  - "Divisive Criteria for Auca Word Classes", May 1962; Peeke, M. Catherine
  - "Seven Categories of Language Classification in Reference to Turkish", May 1966; Premo, Douglas
  - "Original Annals and Historical Traditions of the Linapis...", 1836; Rafinesque, Constantine, translator
  - "Cashibo", n.d.; Shell, Olive A.
  - "Problems Posed by the Walam Olum", 1948; [Speck, F. G.]
    -See also Ser. III-A, Walam Olum-- Voegelin Translation #4
  - ., Taylor, Douglas MacRae
    - "An Aberrant Case of Intimate Borrowing", Sep. 1950
    - "Central American Carib: Morphology of the Noun", May 1948
      -See also Ser. I, Taylor, Douglas MacRae, 7 Sep. 1948
    - "The Formative BA in the Language of the Black Carib of Central America", Aug. 1950
    - ["Locators"], [ca. 1950]
    - ["Notes on Carib Nouns"], [ca. 1950]
    - ["Notes on the Carib Utterance"], [ca. 1950]
    - "Preliminary Outline of the Phonology of Central American Carib", Jan. 1950
    - "Semantic Basis in Island Carib", Mar. 1950
    - "Some Island Carib Verb Particles", [ca. 1950]
    - "Substitution in Island Carib", [ca. 1950]
  - "An Outline of English Structure: Introduction I. Phonology--with Henry Lee Smith, Jr., 1949; Traeger, G.L.
  - "Suffixation in Tarascan", May 1956; Wares, Alan C.
  - "Oaxaca Chontal Phonemes", n.d.; Waterhouse, Viola
    -See also Ser. V-A, Chontal
  - "List of Central American Indian Languages", [1949?]; Wonderly, William L.
    -See also Ser. I, Wonderly, William
    -See also Ser V-A, South American and Other Latin American Languages
- Series V. Research Notes, 1925-1967
  - Subseries V-A: Language Notes, 1925-1967
    Contains primarily handwritten and some typed notes on languages and is arranged alphabetically by language. The original titles that Voegelin gave these files were retained, although the spelling of the titles now conforms to C.F and F.M. Voegelin's Classification and Index of the World's Languages. Files on Delaware, Hopi, Southern Paiute, and Uto-Aztecan are the most extensive. Some files included only reprints, which were removed to the APS library and replaced in the folder with a photocopy of the title page. Formal narrative works describing a particular language are filed either in Series III-B or IV.
    - Amazon Indian Languages, 1940 (Box Series V a: AM-CAR)
      in Spanish
    - Blackfoot, n.d.
    - Carib, [ca. 1949]
      Includes Black, Central American, and Island Carib
    - Cashibo (Pano Family), n.d. (Box Series V a: CAS-K)
    - Chontal, 1925, n.d.
      -See also Ser. IV, Waterhouse, Viola
    - Cuicateco, n.d.
    - Delaware
      -See also Ser. V-B, Delaware--"The Cannibal, Delaware--"The Mermaid"; "Punishment for Disbelief in Mermaids"
      - Folder #1, 1937, 1939
      - Folder #2, n.d.
    - Delaware--Munsee
    - Hopi, n.d.; 6 Folders
    - Iroquois, n.d.
    - Kaingang, n.d.
    - Kraho, 1955, n.d.
    - Macro Tucanoan, n.d. (Box Series V a: MA-UT)
    - Maku, n.d.
    - Mixtecan Family, 1966
    - Ojibwa and Pottowatomi--Comparative Vocabularies
    - [Oneida?], n.d.
    - Ottawa, n.d.
    - Paiute, Southern
      - Folder #1, 20 Jun. 1959
      - Folder #2, 8 Aug. 1961
      - Folder #3, [ca. 1960]
      - Folder #4, [ca. 1960]
      - Folder #5, [ca. 1960
    - Pame, northern, n.d.
      -See also Ser. IV, Gibson, Lorna F.
    - Pottowatomi
      See Ser. V-A, Ojibwa and Pottowatomi--Comparative Vocabularies
    - Quechua, 1967, n.d.
      -See also Ser. IV, Orr, Carolyn
    - Seneca, n.d.
      -See also Ser. V-B, Seneca--"Autobiographies"; "Medicine Witchcraft"; Turtle Rattles"
    - Shawnee, n.d.
    - [Shawnee?], n.d.
    - Shiriana, 1964-1965
    - Sierra Popoluca, 1947-1948, n.d.
    - Siouan--Iroquois, n.d.
    - South American and Other Latin American Languages, [1949?]
      Includes Central American and Mexico
    - Tarascan, 1956
    - Uru, 1967
    - Uto-Aztecan, n.d.; 2 Folders
  - Subseries V-B: Texts, (See also Ser. VI), 1946-1952
    Series V-B: Texts
    Contains unbound (see Ser. VI for bound texts) hand- and typewritten notes and drafts of transcriptions and translations of brief Native American narratives, songs, tales, and conversations. The texts are arranged alphabetically first by language and then by title of text. If the format of two or more texts indicates that they were intended to be kept together as a unit, e.g., consecutive page numbering, then the texts are foldered together and filed under the first title. The greatest number of unbound texts are in the Delaware files.
    - Carib (Box Series V b: CA-UN)
      - "The Story of a Wicked Aunt", Mar. 1948
      - "Story of a Woman's Three Children", [ca. 1949]
      - Tale, Feb. 1948
      - Three Conversations and a Letter, [ca. 1949]
    - Delaware, n.d.
      - "The Cannibal", n.d.
      - ["Coffeemill"], n.d.
      - "Crazy Jack", n.d.
      - "Gambling", n.d.
      - "How Caddo Made a Treaty", n.d.
      - "How the Word 'Delaware' Got Started", n.d.
      - "How Wampum is Made", n.d.
      - "How W.L. Interpreted for the First White Man He Ever Saw", n.d.
      - "Hunting in the Old Days", n.d.
      - "The Mermaid"; "Punishment for Disbelief in Mermaids", n.d.
      - "Prayer by Mrs. Lucy Davis", n.d.
      - "Way of Curing Snakebite", n.d.
      - "When the Creator Was Drunk", n.d.
      - "W.L. and Bighouse"
      - "W.L.'s Grandmother"
      - "W.L.'s Sickness and Vision"
      - Songs, n.d.
      - Munsee--"The Creation", n.d.
        [and other texts from Cephas Snake]
    - Guarani--"Pisaim" and "Blessed Lake"
    - Ojibwa, eastern--"The Walpole Island"
      [and others]
    - Paiute, Southern
      - "Conversation Between Vivan and Leroy"
        -See Ser V-A, Paiute, Southern #5
      - "How the Eagle Got Black Feathers", n.d.
      - "Southern Paiute Text", n.d.
        -See also Ser. V-A, Uto-Aztecan
      - "Why the Coyote Cries at Night and in the Morning"
    - Seneca
      - "Autobiographies", n.d.
      - "Buffalo Story", 1946
      - [Conversations], n.d.
      - "Medicine Witchcraft", n.d.
      - "Turtle Rattles", n.d.
    - [Seneca]--"Chipmunk and Bear" [and others]
    - Shawnee--"Unique Shawnee Texts", 1952
    - Unidentified--Dialogue between Velma Bear Hat and Margaret Water Chief
  - Subseries V-C: Other, 1966, n.d.
    Series V-C: Other
    Contains clippings and manuscript and typewritten notes regarding Voegelin's research interests. This subseries includes notes taken by Voegelin on several linguistics articles and on the history of the Linguistic Institute. Files are arranged alphabetically by subject title.
    - Clippings, 1966, n.d. (Box Series V c: C-W)
    - Inscribed Stone and Syllabary Material
      -See also Ser. VII, Inscribed Stone
    - Linguistic Institute, n.d.
    - Notes From Journal Article Readings, n.d.
    - [Scientific vs. Colloquial Terms], 1966, n.d.
    - Williams, Angeline--Genealogy, n.d.
      Ottawa informant
- Series VI. Notebooks, 1934, 1940-1941
  contains handwritten notes and texts, along with any handwritten or typed materials found in or with the notebooks. Languages of the Blackfoot, Delaware, Ojibwa, Pottowatomi, Seneca, and Shawnee are represented. The bulk of material in this series is in Shawnee (37 folders) and Ojibwa (24 folders). Shawnee notebooks primarily contain texts, and almost every notebook is accompanied by handwritten notes and typescripts of transcriptions and translations. Contents of the Blackfoot and Ojibwa notebooks were described in detail by Richard A. Rhodes, Department of Linguistics at the University of California-Berkeley, in 1988. Blackfoot and Ojibwa notebooks are arranged in the order of Rhodes' list, a photocopy of which is filed in the first Blackfoot folder.
  - Blackfoot, n.d.; 3 Folders (Box Series VI: BL - OJIBWA #2)
  - Delaware
    -See Ser. VI, Blackfoot
  - Ojibwa
    - Folders #1-2, 1940
    - Folder #3-5, 1941 (Box Series VI: OJIBWA #3-9)
    - Folders #6-9, n.d.
    - Folders #10-13, n.d. (Box Series VI: OJIBWA #10-21)
    - Folder #14, 18-21 Jun. 1941
    - Folder #15, 24-28 Jun. 1941
    - Folder #16, 2 Jul. 1941
    - Folder #17, 8 Jul. 1941
    - Folder #18, 15-19 Jul. 1941
    - Folder #19, 9 Jul. 1941
    - Folder #20, Aug. 1941
    - Folder #21, Aug. 1941
    - Folder #22, 1941 (Box Series VI: OJIBWA #22 - SHAWNEE #3)
    - Folder #23, 11 Aug. 1941
    - Folder #24, n.d.
  - Pottowatomi, n.d.
  - Penobscot
    -See Ser. VI, Ojibwa #24
  - Seneca, n.d.; 2 Folders
  - Shawnee
    - Folders #1-3, [1934]
    - Folders #4-16, [1934] (Box Series VI: SHAWNEE #4-16)
    - Folders #17-31, [1934] (Box Series VI: SHAWNEE #17-31)
    - Folders #32-36, [1934] (Box Series VI: SHAWNEE #32-37)
    - Folder 37, n.d.
- Series VII. Photograph, 1936?
  Native American Images note: Colorful linguistic maps, in pencil and crayon, of the Potawatomi, Delaware, and Shawnee tribes to accompany the texts of C.F. Voegelin’s work on Algonquian languages. North American areas covered include Lower Michigan, Northern Wisconsin, Northern Indiana, and Central Illinois. One map covers the indigenous languages of Veracruz. Of particular note, a black and white silver gelatin print of a Potawatomi petroglyphic rock in Elkhart, Indiana. Primarily works by Voegelin, some maps were produced by his anthropology students. Some images are housed in Series III, IV, and Oversize.
  - Inscribed stone, Potawatomi petroglyphs, Elkhart, Indiana, 1936; 3 x 4 " gelatin silver prints (2)
    - Inscribed stone, 1936
    - Inscribed stone, 1936
  - Algonquina langauge text with illustrations, 1936; 3 1/2 x 4 1/2" Negatives (7)
  - Newman, M.T. Linguistic classification of the Southern New England Algonquians, 13 1/2 x 10" crayon map
  - Howe, B. Indian language groups in the state of Illinois, 1938; 8 1/2 x 11" ink maps (3)
  - Voegelin, C.F. Walam Olum--Map of North America. Delaware Indians, 1936-1938; 18 x 12 1/2" ink map
  - Voegelin, C.F. American Indian Languages, 1936-1938; 17 x 13" color pencil chart
  - South America and other Latin American languages, 1936-1938; 17 x 15" ink map
- Series III-A, III-B, V-A. Oversized (Os 1)
  - Series III-A, Works Translated by Voegelin
    - Walam Olum-- Voegelin Translation #1, 1946
  - Series III-B, Works Authored by Voegelin
    - American Indian Language
    - Language and Culture, [ca. 1967]
    - "The Linguist's Image of Language", [ca. 1967]
  - Series V-A, Language Notes
    - South American and Other Latin American Languages, [1949?]